cyberastro.com 2003-06-18

# CyberAstro.com - Vedic Astrology for the new Millennium

  |  [](https://www.truste.org/validate/6237) This confirms that Cyber Astro Inc. is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for [http://www.cyberastro.com](http://www.cyberastro.com/)

TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. Because this web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. By displaying the TRUSTe trustmark, this web site has agreed to notify you of :

1.What personally identifiable information of yours or third party personally identification is collected from you through the web site  
2\. The organization collecting the information  
3\. How the information is used  
4\. With whom the information may be shared  
5\. What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information  
6\. The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under (Name of the Company) control  
7\. How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact :

**Gautam Mukerjee**  
Vice President & CFO  
Cyber Astro Ltd.  

If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe <http://www.truste.org/users/users_watchdog.html>  
TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with the Web site to resolve your concerns.

Cyber Astro is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. Because Cyber Astro, Inc. wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have our privacy practices reviewed and audited by TRUSTe.

At Cyber Astro, Inc. we take the privacy of the information you provide us very seriously. This statement demonstrates our firm commitment to our privacy policy. Please read this carefully to understand how we use any information you provide us at [www.cyberastro.com](http://www.cyberastro.com/).

  * Cyber Astro, Inc. guarantees complete confidentiality of our members’ identity, horoscope details and the prediction details. 
  * Cyber Astro, Inc. further guarantees that no direct or indirect use will be made by Cyber Astro about any aspect of life, as revealed in the horoscope of a member, except for the explicit purpose of communicating the horoscope charts and predictions back to the member. 
  * We do not sell or rent your personally identifiable information to anyone. 
  * We allow members to access their users profiles and change information, as they deem necessary. 

Since new items will get added to our services as we modify and expand, we suggest that you check back from time to time in order to understand how we treat your information. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what personal information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we disclose it. Your continued use of the site will constitute your acknowledgment of our Privacy Policy.

This document is rather long because we want to give our users all the facts about our privacy policy. The items below provide an index to the information that follows:

  * What personal information do we collect, and what choices do you have in not providing the information?
  * How do we use this information?
  * What are cookies and how Cyber Astro uses them? 
  * Links to other sites
  * Who has access to your personally identifiable information?
  * How can you correct/update your membership profile or information?
  * What communications do we send you?
  * What is our policy regarding Children's Online Privacy Protection?
  * Who can you contact regarding this Privacy Policy?

**What personal information do we collect?**

**Registration Data**

During membership registration, Cyber Astro collects personal information including your name, gender, and email address, your current hometown and birth data information including your time of birth. This information is used strictly to generate your personal horoscopes online. Your email address is used to identify your unique birth data record in the database, since an email address is always unique and has no duplicates. You do not have to provide any personal information to use Cyber Astro’s services. However, if you choose not to become a member of Club CyberAstro, we may not be able to provide you with some of the other services dependent upon the collection of such information, such as your personalized free predictions.

**Through Log Files**

Our server and statistics server capture information to gather broad demographic information that is not personal. We track the IP address of visitors to the site to find out demographically which parts of the world our traffic comes from. We collect browser types used and access times to analyze trends, administer the site, track users movements within the site to find out what services are most appealing. All of this information is used for gathering broad demographic data to enhance the performance and services of the site.

**Through Order Forms**

For our paid personalized services we gather basically the information needed for fulfillment of the service. This is held in strict confidence, as explained earlier. We guarantee complete confidentiality of our members’ identity, horoscope details and the prediction details. Cyber Astro, Inc. further guarantees that no direct or indirect use will be made by Cyber Astro about any aspect of life, as revealed in the horoscope of a member, except for the explicit purpose of communicating the horoscope charts and predictions back to the member.

For payment of the paid services, we use two independent secure server companies, Bank Card USA for International Cards and Payseal of ICICI Bank Ltd. for Indian Credit cards. Your credit card information, as well as your address for address verification is collected by this company on their website and Cyber Astro, Inc. has no access to this information.

**Other information that we may collect**

Any other information we may have for you, comes from actual email or other contact you may have made with us in regard to specific services or products. As a general rule, these are not made part of your member profile, and are used only to address your specific need or concern that you may have communicated to us on. Although we give you the option to tell your friends about our site, we do not monitor or keep any record of friends you may contact. Information gathered on our “Affiliate with Us”, is used primarily for a Business-to-Business purpose and to encourage inquiries from other web sites that might be interested in obtaining our Astrology Content for their own site. Information from “Advertise with Us” similarly is used to generate interest in other sites or companies that may wish to purchase banner advertising on our site.

**How do we use this information?**

We use the personal information you supply us, including your membership registration data, to enable us to provide you with personalized free predictions. In addition, this information is used in a demographic manner to enhance Cyber Astro’s services, personalize your experience and provide you with special offers and services that we think you will find valuable.

Cyber Astro uses the information described above to do, among other things, the following:

  * Personalize and enhance the site and services such as providing you with your personalized predictions. 
  * Send occasional personalized information about Cyber Astro and its site features, unless you have opted out of receiving these types of communications. 
  * Contact members’ occasionally for feedback regarding Cyber Astro and our services. 

We may also use demographic information we collect to develop summary reports for our own advertising strategy and for other advertisers. An example of a summary report might be "100,000 people clicked on this link and of those people, 35% were members and are above the age of 25." Since our membership is global, we may also track which countries our members live in and whether it might be feasible to offer services in their own language, and make other decisions to enhance your overall experience of the site.  
**What are cookies are and how Cyber Astro uses them?**

Random numbers that are assigned to you to identify you to a site is known as a “cookie". As a standard practice, Cyber Astro assigns a random number to you when you become a member. This number is only activated when you log in as a member, to open your birth data information so that we may deliver personalized predictions based on your birth time and date. Cookies are only served by our server for the session and are not kept on your computer. Without cookies, we would not be able to deliver the personalized predictions to you. It also saves you from having to enter your birth details every time you want a free personalized prediction or “mantra”.

Cyber Astro does not require users to accept cookies in order to enjoy the site. You can set your browser to reject cookies, however, we would not be able to offer you the personalized free predictions that are available on the site.

**Links to other sites**

This site contains links to other sites as described below:

**Banner Ads**

We use an outside ad company to display ads on our site. These ads may contain cookies. While we use cookies in other parts of our Web site, our ad company collects cookies received with banner ads, and we do not have access to this information. Some customer data is shared with the advertising companies, but only in aggregate form. We use [www.Advertising.com](http://www.advertising.com/) and [www.ValueClick.com](http://www.valueclick.com/) currently for ad delivery. We encourage you to visit their respective sites to learn how your information is being used.

**Free Email Services**

Free email services at our domain name @ClubCyberastro.com is provided by [www.Everyone.net](http://www.everyone.net/). Everyone.net is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program.

**What communications do we send you?**

At the current time we send out an automatic Welcome letter from the site when you enroll as a member with your user name and password so that you may use it as a reference in the future. Additionaly, we send you email for your personalized monthly astrological signatures and information regarding new products and services, from time to time. You are provided with an option to unsubscribe from this mailing list at any time. Besides these communications, we bring you special offers from our business associates on their products and services. Once again, you have an option to opt out from receiving such special offers.

**How can you correct/update your membership profile or information?**

You can edit/correct/update your membership information or profile anytime online by using the “Edit Member Profile” link from the Home Page.

**Who has access to your personally identifiable information?**

Your membership information is password-protected so that only you and a few selected people at Cyber Astro have access to this personal information. You may edit your membership data anytime by using the” Edit Profile” feature on the site, and once again it is password protected.

All Cyber Astro employees sign a nondisclosure and confidentiality agreement and are reminded of the need for security and confidentiality at all times. Your information is accessible only to key people at Cyber Astro, and is looked at only on a need only basis.

Although, we treat our members as part of our extended family, we truly operate in a world of virtual reality, where the only personal information we have for you is your email address to disclose your identity. Since this is not linked to either an address of a phone number, we guarantee the confidentiality of your information.

**Children's Online Privacy Protection**

This website is in compliance and with accordance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we do not allow any information of children under 13 to be taken without parental consent or parental notification. As a general rule, and in keeping with the subject matter of the site, normally adults enroll children in order to obtain horoscope predictions for them. While we do not encourage this practice, we do require all information for children is acknowledged by parental consent in our membership registration form and in all our order forms.

**Who can you contact regarding this Privacy Policy?**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact:

**Gautam Mukerjee**  
Vice President & CFO  
Cyber Astro Ltd.  
Cyber House  
35 (4 Bays)  
Echelon Institutional Area  
Sector 32  
Gurgaon 122 002  
Haryana  
India
